あっははは…
What a surprise to meet with
you again like this!
再び そなたと
このような形で
まみえることに なろうとはなあ
What?
何？
I didn't think you'd recover
from those wounds,
あれだけの手傷
よもや助かるまいと思うたが
but I see you still live, Rakshain.
生きていたか ラクシャイン
Brother-in-law, traitor!
我が義弟にして 裏切り者よ！
You shall pay for your crimes with your life!
その罪 死をもって償うが いい
What do you mean "traitor"?
裏切り者とは どういう意味だ？
Drop the act!
とぼけるでない
Don't tell me you have forgotten
about your crimes!
その罪 忘れたとは言わせぬぞ
This is all part of your condemnation!
これらは全て 断罪である！
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Unrest
いーはっ！
たあっ
Onward!
進めえ！
-どぉーわあー！
-うわあー！
どぅあっ
Lady Touka!
トウカ殿
Seems the strength of the Evankulga
isn't just an overblown rumor.
エヴェンクルガの強さ
尾ひれのついた噂では無いようですわね
Allying yourself with such evil...
Your sword surely cries!
悪漢に くみするとは
その剣が泣いているぞ
Oh, so you know, m'lady?
お分かりになります？
It cries out for flesh and blood!
血肉を食らいたいと 泣いておりますわ
Lord Orikakan, you should withdraw
from this place for now.
オリカカン殿 ここは一旦引かれよ
I cannot withdraw!
引くわけには いかない
Not while this traitor, who has spilled
the blood of his people,
目前に 民を おのが妻を
his wife and his children,
stands before me!
子供を手にかけた裏切り者がおるのだ
If we lose you now, Lord Orikakan,
今オリカカン殿を失っては
the sacrifice of our fallen comrades
will have been in vain!
散っていった同胞たちに
申し訳が立ちませぬ
うんぬ
とぁあー！
ううーわー！
うへっ
I guess they got away?
逃げられた…
って ことですかねえ
Commander?
総大将
Brother, let me go after them!
兄者 行かせてくれっ
兄者！
Brother!
いえ
No, we shall retreat also.
こちらも引きましょう
It would be impossible to advance
our troops further in this state.
この状況では これ以上の進軍は無理です
Is this the consequence of being
swayed by my emotions?
感情に流された報いか
How is His Highness?
聖上は？
He fell asleep a little while ago.
先ほど眠られました
さすがに 疲れていたみたいで
He was quite exhausted.
無理も ありませんわね
It's only natural.
テオロさんとは
He was very close to Teoro-san.
仲良し… でしたから
エルルゥ あなたも
Eruruu, why don't you get some rest too?
いいえ
No, please let me be with all of you for now.
今は皆さんと いさせてください
ふぅー ははぁー うーん
Aruruu, why don't you go to sleep?
アルルゥ
-うん？
-あなたは お休みなさい
No!
いやぁ
ふぅん
Aruruu...
アルルゥ…
Damn it!
くそーっ
くそー！
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
んぐっ くそー
Damn it! Damn it!
くそー！
呼んでいる
They're calling...
Are you calling me?
私を
呼んでいるのか？
Stop, stop it!
-あぁー
-やめろ
Stay away!
来るな
Do not look at me like that!
そんな目で私を見るな！
I am not the one who made you like this!
お前たちを そんな姿にしたのは私では…
It was not me!
違う！
I... I...
私は
私は…
Who am I!?
誰だ？
ラクシャイン
Rakshain!
You are my brother-in-law, and a traitor!
我が義弟にして 裏切り者！
It was not me!
違う！
How can you keep denying it?
なぜ違うと 言い切れる？
No...
それは…
だはぁっ
うんぐっ
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
You were drenched with sweat, so...
すごい汗だったので
Hakuoro-san?
ハクオロさん？
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
Could you say that once more?
その…
もう一度言ってくれないか？
その… 名前を
That name...
はあ 変なハクオロさん
You're acting weird, Hakuoro-san.
You're tired from the constant struggle
we've been through.
ずっと ずっと 大変でしたから
疲れているんですよ
しばらく休んでいてください
You need to rest for a while.
I cannot do that.
そうも言っていられない
ダメです
No!
If the king falls ill under my care,
then it makes me no good as a healer.
オゥルォ（皇）が体を壊したとあっては
薬師として失格になってしまいます
Thank you.
ありがとう
うふ
You're quite welcome.
どういたしまして
それじゃあ 食事を用意しますね
Well, I'll go put some food on for you.
I don't have much of an appetite...
いやー 食事は…
ダメです
No way, you have to eat to
regain your strength.
ちゃんと食べないと
元気が出ないんですから
It doesn't seem like it's been
long since they left.
そんなに時間は 経っていないみたいです
That means they haven't gone very far then.
奴ら まだ遠くには行ってないってことだ
次は逃しはしない
They won't get away from us the next time!
次があると思っているのか？
Do you think there's going to be a next time?
Evankulga!
エヴェンクルガ！
I was well aware that you'd be tracking us.
お前たちが つけて来ていることなど
承知の上だ
In the name of the Evankulga, I shall
slay all of you who side with evil!
エヴェンクルガの名において
悪漢に くみする お前らを 切る！
Our enemy is alone.
You guys stay out of this.
敵は1人だ
お前たちは手を出すな
えいっ！
うはぁ
つぐぅ
うーやぁー！
ふっ とぅあっ
てぃあ うっ！
てぃあ いやっ
てやっ
いーやっ！
うっ えふっ ふんっ
I've got you now!
もらったー！
You underestimate!
甘い！
うはぁ
ぬはぁー！ ぐあ
-若様ー！
-おっ おお
My lord!
うぐっ
うへっ ううっ
これしきっ
It's nothing...
Go back and tell him,
Justice is on my side.
帰って伝えるがよい
義は我にあり
Your tainted swords shall never touch me!
貴様らの不浄な剣が 我に届くことはない
えっ ええぃっ
Wow! Aru-chan, you've got so many!
アルちゃん すごーい
Yeah, they're for everyone.
皆の分
Okay, let's pick lots and lots of flowers.
いっぱい摘んでいこうね
グルゥゥゥーファー アァァ
ぬあっ ぐぅっ
Was it that woman again?
また あの女か
How pathetic.
情けねえなーあ
What!?
何？
You got your ass beat and ran back home.
結局 やられて帰って来たんじゃねえかあ
Commander, we've just returned.
総大将 今 戻りやした
Right...
So, what about you?
そういうお前は どうなんだ
We located their base camp.
俺は あいつらの陣の位置を掴んだぜ
What?
何っ？
Is that true?
本当ですか？
あっ いや
Huh? Well, it had already been vacated
by the time we found it.
既に もぬけの殻だったんですけどねえ
Those guys sure are a pain.
We can't pin them down.
面倒な連中ですぜえ
場所を掴ませやがらねえ
After all your talk just now,
that's all you've got to offer?
でかい口を叩いて そのザマか
What was that?
-何だとぉ！
-そうだろうが
Am I wrong!?
Um, excuse me...
You do a lot of yappin' yourself
for such a wimp!
-あ あのー
-お前の方こそ 弱いくせに
You do a lot of yappin' yourself
for such a wimp!
-ピーチクパーチクー！
-おっ だとっ！
Speak for yourself!
-貴様こそ！ んんー ふんっ
-んぐぐぅー ふんっ
Kuccha Keccha's strength
lies in their cavalry.
クッチャ・ケッチャの強さは
その機動力を生かした騎馬隊にあります
They attack before we can ready ourselves,
こちらが体勢を整える前に
一気に押し寄せ
and by the time we respond, they've
already withdrawn their forces.
反撃する頃には
既に撤退してしまっている
Furthermore, because they keep moving their
base camp, we cannot surround them.
そして 陣が絶えず移動するため
実体を掴ませません
But the most dangerous element...
何より厄介なのが…
Is that woman.
あの女ですわね
The Evankulga Clan,
エヴェンクルガ族
They are a small tribe that
live in the highlands.
高地に住む少数民族
Each of them is gifted enough
in the sword arts
それぞれが 武士として名を残すほど
to be called a warrior in his
or her own right.
武の資質に恵まれた者たち
They will not stray from their code of honor,
even if it could cost them their lives.
例え おのが命を失おうとも
決して義に反することはないでしょう
Wait a minute! Are you saying that
they have a sense of morality?
待て
それは 連中の方に
大義があるっていうのか？
Yet, there is definitely a certain degree of unrest
between the civilians and soldiers.
しかし 民や兵の間に
動揺が走っていることは 確かです
ぬぁぁ
Could this have something to do
with Your Highness's lost past?
もしや 聖上の失われた過去に…
関係しているのでは？
うぅぬ
Your pardon, please disregard
my careless remark.
失言でした
お忘れください
In any case, having an Evankulga as our
adversary, will make for a difficult battle.
とにかく 敵に
エヴェンクルガが いることで
この戦 厳しいものに なるかと
Say, everyone?
あのー 皆さん
My grandma used to say that when
you're stuck on a problem,
おばあちゃんが言ってました
悩みで行き詰まった時
if you dwell on it, you won't
be able to find a solution.
その事ばかりを考えていたら
かえって抜け出せないって
She said that at times like this,
it's best to talk about it over some tea.
そんな時は お茶でも飲んで
くつろぐのが 一番だって
You're right, that may indeed be true.
そうだな
そうかも知れない
It's delicious.
うまい
Yes...
はい
Wonderful!
良かったぁ
There is one odd thing here.
１つ 妙なことがある
Yes?
はい？
Kuccha Keccha is almost entirely flat plains.
クッチャケッチャは
その ほぼ全体が平原となっている
That's why they're able to freely move
about the area in all directions.
だから 奴らはその中を
縦横無尽に駆け巡ることができる
There is but one exception.
だが １つだけ
A deep ravine runs through this mountain range
and divides the country geographically.
ここの山脈が深い渓谷となって
国を両断している
To cross to the other side of the gorge,
反対側に行こうとするなら
下から遠回りしないと行けません
they would have to go down and
take the long way around.
それなのに…
And yet... Is that it?
ですね
Right...
Dori, Gura...
ドリィ グラァ
Yes, sir.
はい
実は僕たちで 敵の跡をつけて
その移動路を調べていたんですが
Actually, we've been following the enemy
and tracking their movements,
but we keep losing track of them
right in this area.
この辺りで 何度か見失ってしまうんです
The next thing we know,
we see them on the other side.
そしたら いつの間にか
向こう側に その姿があって
The natural conclusion would be that
there is a bridge in the area.
どこかに 向こうに渡る橋か何かが
あると考えるのが 自然ですね
But we do not know exactly where.
しかし その場所が分からない
Damn! Where?
くそー どこだあ
どこにある
Where is it!?
Here!
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
What happened to you?
How did you get all scraped up?
どうしたの こんな擦り傷だらけで
-こ こ… う…
-アルルゥ こことは？
Aruruu, what spot do you mean?
There's a bridge here.
ここに橋 ある
How do you know this?
なぜ そんなことが分かる？
We followed their scent and
found the bridge. Right?
臭いを追ってったら 橋あった
ねえ
Right!
ねえー
Don't give me that!
“ねえー”では ありません
-ああ
-ウゴォウ
These children willfully snuck out
of the castle on their own!
この子たちったら
勝手に城を抜け出したりして
What!? Aruruu, where did you go?
アルルゥ
-うっ
-いったい どこへ行っていたの？
Lost your voice, Camus?
カミュ 答えられないのですか？
う うぅーん
Aruruu! Mukkuru!
アルルゥ
ムックル！
Grandma's place...
おばあちゃんの とこ
ぬぅぅ
You went to Yamayura?
ヤマユラに
Please don't yell at Aru-chan!
おじ様
アルちゃんを叱らないで
For flowers...
お花
I see.
そうか
I'm sure they will make everyone happy.
きっと皆も喜ぶ
Uh-huh...
Thank you...
ありがとう
Thank you.
Call the troops, we're moving out!
招集をかけろ
出るぞ！
Sir!
-はっ！
-おう！
In a place like this, huh? Tricky bastards...
よくも こんな所に
No wonder we couldn't find it.
これは見つからないわけよねえ
グゥ
It just goes to show how great you are.
あなたが偉いってことですわ
Then let's knock it the hell down!
じゃ とっとと落としちまいやしょうぜ
Stop!
待て
You again!
また貴様かあ
いつまでも隠し通せるものではないと
思っていたが
I knew we couldn't keep it hidden forever,
but you have found it faster than I expected.
意外と早かったな
We've got someone on our side with
an amazing sense of smell.
うちには鼻が利く
すごいのが いるんですのよ
グォー
ふん
I take it Rakshain's comrades
are a pack of beasts then?
ラクシャインの仲間は
獣揃いということか
What!?
何っ！
Now that you have found this place,
I can no longer go easy on you.
ここを見つけられた以上
手加減するわけには いかない
Today, you're going down!
今日こそはっ
うっ うん！ だあっ！
ふん んっ！
My Kuccha Kecchan comrades...
クッチャ・ケッチャの同士よ
Now you're the only one left!
残るは 貴様１人
The outcome is as you see.
ご覧の通りです
Now, please lay down your weapon,
warrior of the Evankulga.
投降してください
エヴェンクルガの武士よ
Upon my honor, the honor of the Evankulga,
某はエヴェンクルガ
我が誇りに懸けて
I will not yield to you villains!
悪漢に屈するわけにはいかぬ！
Tell me.
教えてくれ
Who is this Rakshain?
ラクシャインとは誰だ？
Even now, you still pretend not to know?
この期に及んで まだとぼけるつもりか
Very well, I'll say it as many
times as you like.
いいだろう 何度でも言ってやる
You are a despicable man,
貴様は何百もの同胞を手にかけ
who has stolen the lives of hundreds
of your own comrades, Rakshain!
命を奪った忌むべき男
ラクシャイン！
You wench!
貴様！
Well, I guess I have no choice.
仕方が ありませんわね
H.. Hey!
おっ おい
If you're not going to get out of the way...
そこを どいて頂けないのでしたら…
くどい！
Enough talk!
ふんっ！
ぬはっ
-いやー！
-てぇー！
ふやぁ！ うっ
おぐっ
Karula!
カルラ！
Oh, right...
そうでしたわね
What's the matter?
どうした？
It certainly was enjoyable though.
折角 楽しかったのですけど
何？
What!?
Well then, be seeing you.
それでは ご機嫌よう
なはっ
貴様らー！
Damn you!
Rakshain!
ラクシャイーン！
Hey...
おい
うふっ
So that's all it took to defeat
the great Evankulga?
エヴェンクルガが これぐらいで
おとう… さん
Father?
Who is Rakshain?
ラクシャインとは…
Who am I?
私は…
誰だ
Ah, Eruruu, what brings you at this hour?
エルルゥか
どうした こんな夜更けに？
Were you still awake?
まだ起きてたんですか
Yeah, I could not sleep.
ああ 眠れなくて
I'm sorry, but could you
bring me more sake?
すまない
酒を持って来てくれ
You've already had quite a lot though...
でも もう かなり飲んで…
頼む
Please.
Say, the weather was nice
today, wasn't it?
えーと その… 今日は
いいお天気でしたね
Was it?
そうか
We all did the laundry today, and then...
だから 皆でお洗濯したんです
-そしたら…
-そうか…
Oh yeah?
I...
私は…
はぁ はい
Yes?
They say that I killed my
own wife and children.
私は
自分の妻と子供を殺した男なのだそうだ
Had you heard about that already?
既に聞いているか
What? Those people are just making it all up.
そんなの あの人たちが
勝手に言っているだけで
嘘に決まっています
It's obviously a lie!
What if it is the truth though?
What then?
本当だとしたら
どうする？
What if I did kill my wife and children?
自分が本当に
妻と子を殺したのだとしたら…
That couldn't...
そんなこと…
Couldn't be possible?
あり得ない？
It is not impossible.
あり得ないことではない
I have no memories of what
I have done up until now.
今まで何をしてきたのか 記憶が無いんだ
Anything could be possible.
何をしていたとしても 不思議ではない
I had no idea...
知らなかった
いや 考えないように していたのか
Or maybe I tried not to think about it.
Having no memories is such an
unnerving, frightening thing.
記憶が無いというのは
こんなにも不安で 怖いものなんだな
I'm sure it's some kind of mistake!
きっと 何かの間違いですから
So please try not to worry about it!
だから 気にしない方が いいです
I've only been with you for a short
while now, but I already know.
今まで と言っても 少しの間ですけど
でも その間を一緒にいた
私には分かります
You're not the kind of person
that would do such a thing!
ハクオロさんは そんなことを
する人じゃないって
I will always be by your side,
no matter what.
何があっても 私は ずっとそばにいます
So please...
だから…
Please!
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
A Bloody Battle